Hello my name is Emad  El Yehya
and i'm from the BeirutByByte team and
I will be demoing the project that we did for the third challenge of MIT's refugee learning accelerator
Initially we had to plan to film a person using this as he approaches the Bluetooth beacon as well as his interactions with the phone
But due to some technical difficulties were not able to put the AR into Android so we will demo the different components individually
I'll start by turning on Bluetooth. I'm near the beacon so the notification should pop up pretty soon and there we are
Alright, so there's obviously an instructions page for when the app is run for the first time
But I didn't show it for brevity's sake
So what the user should do is he usually directed towards this symbol
And then the AR would begin since this part is not incorporated
We've hard coded the app to just run directly to the next stage and we'll demo now the AR part
After the symbol has been identified and the video has been played, the camera exits and shows the learner the conversation he has just heard
He can click on any sentence
And then the sentence would be spoken out loud to him and he can
Hear that as many times as he wants and there's obviously an Arabic translation there as well
Sadly Google does not allow internal recording
So there's no way for us to show you the voice however the voice is exactly the same as the voice that has appeared
during the
video itself
Now when the when the learner is done
He simply presses continue, and it goes back to the recording stage where he can look for other symbols
Note that previewing the same symbol on the same day
We show him the same segment as he had seen before
This is because we believe that bite-sized lessons are best for casual learning as well as the fact that this will help the learner
review the conversation after having gotten everything translated for him, which further enforces his understanding of the
Concepts we're trying to get across